unsdsn.org 2019-12-30

# Sustainable Development Solutions Network

SDSN Association Inc. (hereafter referred to as “SDSN”) is the data controller in charge of processing personal data of any users of online offering provided by the SDSN, including but not limited to online education under the SDG Academy. You can find our contact details on our websites [www.unsdsn.org](http://www.unsdsn.org/), [www.sdgacademy.org](http://www.sdgacademy.org/), and other websites operated by the SDSN and identified in this Privacy Policy. The contacts for questions concerning processing of the personal data are named directly in this Privacy Policy.

The SDSN is strongly committed to protecting your privacy and your private and personal data. We collect, save, and use your personal data strictly in accordance with the provisions of this Privacy Policy and the applicable data protection provisions, including the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and national data protection provisions.

With this Privacy Policy, we wish to inform you to what extent and for what purpose your personal data is processed in connection with the use of our online offering.

Personal data

Personal data is all information about an identified or identifiable individual. This includes information about your identity such as your name, your e-mail address, or your postal address. Any information that cannot be directly linked to your identity (e.g. statistical details such as the number of users of the online offering) is, however, not considered to be personal data.

You can browse our website without disclosing your identity and without providing any personal data. In that case, we will merely collect general information about your visit to our online offering. However, some of the online services offered require you to provide certain personal data. As a rule, we will process such data only for purposes connected with the use of this online offering, including without limitation for the provision of the desired information. Whenever personal data is collected, you are only required to provide the data that is absolutely essential. Also, you may be asked to provide additional details, which are optional information provided voluntarily. We let you know in each case whether the input fields are for mandatory or optional details. More specific details are provided in the relevant section of this Privacy Policy.

There is no automated decision-making on the basis of your personal data in connection with the use of our online offering.

 **Processing personal data**

We store the information provided by you on protected dedicated servers located outside the European Union. Technical and organisational measures are taken to protect such servers against loss, destruction, access, modification, or dissemination of your data by unauthorized persons. Access to your data will be permitted only to a limited number of persons in charge of the technical, commercial, or editorial support of the servers. Notwithstanding regular controls, full protection against all risks cannot be provided.

 **Disclosure of personal data to third parties**

We use your personal information exclusively for providing the services that you have requested from us. Insofar as we use external service providers in performing the service requested, such external service providers will also access the data exclusively for the purpose of performing the service. By taking the necessary technical and organisational measures we ensure compliance with privacy policies and we demand the same of our external partners.

Moreover, we will not disclose the data to any third parties, including without limitation for advertising purposes, without your express consent. We will disclose your personal data only if you have given your consent to disclosure of the data or insofar as we are entitled or obligated to do so under legal provisions and/or administrative or judicial orders. This may include, without being limited to, giving information for purposes of criminal prosecution, in order to avert danger, or in order to enforce intellectual property rights.

 **Legal basis of data processing**

The SDSN complies with the GDPR in relation to its users based in the European Union. Throughout this document, references to the GDPR apply to individuals and organizations who are covered by the GDPR.

Insofar as we obtain your consent to processing your personal data, Article 6(1)(a) of the GDPR constitutes the legal basis for such data processing.

Insofar as we process your personal data because processing is necessary for the performance of a contract or is necessary under a quasi-contractual relationship with you, the lawfulness of data processing is based on Article 6(1)(b) of the GDPR.

Insofar as we process your personal data because processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation, the lawfulness of data processing is based on Article 6(1)(c) of the GDPR.

Furthermore, Article 6(1)(f) of the GDPR may constitute the legal basis for data processing, if processing of your personal data is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the SDSN or by a third party, except where such interests are overridden by your interests or your fundamental rights and freedoms which require protection of personal data.

Throughout this Privacy Policy, we always point to the legal basis underlying our processing of your personal data.

 **Deletion of data and duration of storage**

We invariably delete or block any personal data provided by you when the purpose of storage of such data ceases to apply. However, we may continue to store your personal data beyond that, if such storage is governed by legal provisions to which we are subject, including without limitation the legal obligation to retain business records and documentation. In such a case, we will delete or block the personal data after the prescribed period of time has expired.

 **Use of our online offering**

 **The SDSN online offering**

The SDSN provides and operates the following websites:

The SDSN provides the following websites, which are managed by SDSN Youth:

The SDSN also operates a number of email listservs that all share the email domain unsdsn.org or sdgacademy.org. SDSN social media offerings offered through third-party platforms are identified below.

 **Use of cookies**

Like many other websites, our Online Offering uses cookies. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer and store certain settings and data of your web browser for the exchange with our Online Offering. As a rule, a cookie contains the name of the domain from which the cookie file has been sent as well as information about the age of the cookie and an alphanumeric identifier.

Cookies enable us recognise your computer and make any default settings immediately available. Cookies help us to improve our Online Offering and to provide you with an even better service customised to meet your particular requirements. This also constitutes a legitimate interest in the processing of the data in accordance with Article 6(1)(f) of the GDPR.

The cookies we use are so-called session cookies that are automatically deleted after the end of the browser session. In individual cases, we may use cookies with a longer storage time so that your default settings and preferences may be considered when you visit our Online Offering the next time.

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. However, you can disable the storage of cookies or set up your web browser to inform you when you receive a cookie. It is also possible to manually delete stored cookies in the browser settings. Please note that your use of our Online Offering may be limited or restricted if you refuse to save cookies or delete necessary cookies.

 **Analytics**

Our Online Offering(s) use third-party cookies set by analytics providers to collect data about website activity (e.g., page views, search terms, date and time of visit, browser and operating system, IP address). These analytics cookies help us understand how our services are being used, better understand the interests of website visitors, and improve our websites to enhance the visitor experience.

When storing website visitor data, certain data, including without limitation visitors’ IP addresses, device and domain data, is stored in shortened and/or encrypted form so that the individual user cannot be identified based on the data. The data collected is never merged with other existing data, e.g. for the purpose of identifying an individual.

These purposes at the same time constitute a legitimate interest within the meaning of the legal basis for data processing in accordance with Article 6(1)(f) of the GDPR.

 **Registration**

You can register for the use of our Online Offering. To register, you have to provide the data requested during registration, such as your name, country of residency and e-mail address. In addition, we record the date and time of registration. During the registration process, we ask for your consent to using your data. That gives you the advantage of not having to enter this data every time you wish to use our online service or to place an order.

If you give your consent, processing of data provided for registration purposes is based on Article 6(1) (a) of the GDPR. If you register with us for the purposes of performance or initiation of a contract, the legal basis for processing of the data is additionally constituted by Article 6(1)(b) of the GDPR.

Upon registration, an account is created for you. You can at any time demand deletion of your account.

 **Communication with us**

There are various ways of contacting us, including but not limited to the contact email addresses on our website. In addition, we will be happy to inform you regularly by e-mailing you our newsletters which deal with various topics.

 **Newsletter**

If you subscribe to one of our newsletters or email listservs, we will use your e-mail address for information purposes of the SDSN until you unsubscribe from the newsletter or the email listserv. You will be regularly updated by e-mail on current topics related to our projects and receive e-mails informing you of special occasions such as new studies and events. Such e-mails may be personalised and individualised on the basis of information we have about you.

If you have subscribed to our newsletter, your consent constitutes the legal basis for processing of your data in accordance with Article 6(1)(a) of the GDPR.

If you do no longer wish to receive our newsletters, you can revoke your consent at any time with effect for the future and/or object to receiving the newsletter without incurring any costs other than the transmission costs in accordance with the basic tariffs. Simply use the unsubscribe link contained in every newsletter or send a message to us at [privacy@unsdsn.org](mailto:privacy@unsdsn.org).

 **Social Media**

Our Online Offering contains links or plugins to the social networks Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, Mobilize, EdCast, Mailchimp, Reddit, YouTube and google+. The links are identified by the logo of their relevant providers.

Clicking on a link opens the relevant social media web pages; this Privacy Policy does not apply to such web pages. For further details on the provisions applicable on such web pages please refer to the relevant Privacy Policies of each of the providers; you can find them at:

No personal information is forwarded to the relevant providers before clicking on the links or calling up a plugin. Calling up the linked website also constitutes the basis for data processing by the relevant website provider.  

 **Use of YouTube**

Our Online Offering contains videos for which we use plugins from the Google-run site YouTube (“YouTube”). The operator of the service is YouTube LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA. If you call up an internet page of our Online Offering which contains a video, a connection with the YouTube servers is created. On that occasion, the YouTube server is told which internet pages of our Online Offering you have visited.

If you are logged in to your YouTube account at that time, you allow YouTube to directly associate your browsing behaviour with your personal profile. You can prevent that by logging out of your YouTube account first. For further information on the handling of user data please refer to the [Google Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) which also applies to YouTube.

Using YouTube enables us to show you videos and give you more information on ourselves and our projects; this at the same time constitutes our legitimate interest within the meaning of Article 6(1)(f) of the GDPR.

 **Your rights**

We, the SDSN, are committed to explaining how we process personal data and to inform you about your rights as transparently as possible. If you want more detailed information or wish to exercise your rights, you can contact us at any time so that we can take care of your concerns.

 **Rights of persons concerned**

You have extensive rights with respect to the processing of your personal data. Individuals and organizations covered by the GDPR have important rights. In summary, those include:

  * Fair processing of information and transparency over how we use your personal information
  * Access to personal information and to certain other supplementary information that this policy is designed to address
  * Correction of any mistakes in the information we hold
  * Erasure of personal information concerning you in certain situations
  * Receiving the personal information concerning you which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and the right to transmit those data to a third party in certain situations
  * Objecting at any time to processing of personal information concerning you for direct marketing
  * Objecting to decisions being taken by automated means which produce legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affect you
  * Objecting in certain other situations to our continued processing of your personal information
  * Otherwise restricting our processing of your personal information in certain circumstances

If you wish to assert any of your rights and/or want more detailed information concerning your rights, please email us at [privacy@unsdsn.org](mailto:privacy@unsdsn.org) or [privacy@sdgacademy.org](mailto:privacy@sdgacademy.org).

 **Revocation of consent and objection**

You may at any time revoke your consent with future effect. Revocation of the consent does not affect the legality of any processing performed on the basis of such consent given up until the revocation thereof. In such cases, too, please use our contact form to get in touch with our staff and/or our data protection officer.

Insofar as the processing of your personal data is not based on consent given by you but on another legal basis, you can object to the data processing. Your objection will lead to a review and, if necessary, to termination of the data processing. You will be informed of the outcome of the review and – if the data processing is to be continued after all – you will receive further information from us on why the data processing is admissible.

 **Data protection officer**

We have appointed a data protection officer who you can contact directly. If you have questions regarding our handling of personal data or if you require other information on data protection issues, please do not hesitate to contact our Data Protection Officer via e-mail at [privacy@unsdsn.org](mailto:privacy@unsdsn.org).

 **Complaints**

If you are of the opinion that the processing of your personal data does not comply with this Privacy Policy or the applicable data protection provisions, you can file a complaint with our data protection officer. Our data protection officer will review the matter and inform you of the outcome of the review. In addition, you are entitled to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

 **Further information**

 **Links to other websites**

Our online service may contain links to other websites. Generally, these links are identified as such. We cannot control to what extent linked websites comply with the applicable data protection provisions. We therefore recommend that for other providers’ data protection statements, you refer to the information given on their respective websites.

 **Amendments of this Privacy Policy**

Any revision of this Privacy Policy is identified by the date specified (see below). We reserve the right to amend this Privacy Policy at any time with effect for the future. Amendments will be made, among other things, in case of technical adjustments of the Online Offering or changes of the data protection laws. The Privacy Policy as amended from time to time is always made available directly through our Online Offering. We recommend obtaining information on any changes of this Privacy Policy on a regular basis.

This Privacy Policy was last revised in: **June 2018**
